survs.com 2018-08-30

# Privacy Policy | Survs

Survs ("Survs" or the "Service") is a service offered through the URL survs.com (the "Website"). Survs is owned and operated by Enough Pepper Lda. ("Survs", "we", or "us"). For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, a "User" ("Creator" or "Survey Creator") is a person who creates surveys, and a "Respondent" is a person who answers those surveys. Survs takes the privacy of its users seriously. This Privacy Policy outlines the details of our commitment to user privacy and security. This document will let you know what information we collect through Survs and how we use that information. The information we receive from Survey Creators and survey Respondents and how we handle it differs, so we have split some sections of this privacy policy into two parts. 

## 1\. Information we collect

### Information we collect directly from Creators

We collect information relating to Creators from a variety of sources:

  * **Registration:** Creators need a Survs account before they can create surveys on Survs. When Creators register we ask for username, email address, time zone and password.
  * **Billing:** When Creators decide to upgrade their account, we require them to provide: name, billing address and credit card details.
  * **Address book:** We allow Creators to import email addresses into a list of contacts so they can easily invite people to take surveys via email. We only use these email addresses to send email invitations on Creators' behalf and at their direction.
  * **Survey:** We store Creators' survey data and provide analysis tools for them to use with respect to this data.

### Information we collect directly from Respondents

We collect information relating to Respondents from surveys hosted by Survs on behalf and upon instructions of the Survey Creator.

  * **Responses to surveys:** We collect and store the Survs responses from Respondents. The Survey Creator is responsible for that data and manages it. The Survey Creator is usually the same person that invited the Respondent to take the survey and sometimes they have their own privacy policy. When responding to a survey, Respondents may provide personal information or data. Survs is not responsible for the content of surveys, so if Respondents have any questions about a survey, they should contact the Survey Creator directly.
  * **Email address:** We collect the email address if the Survey Creator provides it to us in order to send Respondents a survey invitation email. Respondents may opt out of receiving email invitations to complete surveys that are sent by Survey Creators via Survs.

### Information we collect indirectly from Creators and Respondents

  * **Analytics data:** As is true of most websites, we gather certain analytics information automatically. This information is anonymous and includes IP address, browser type, and operating system.

## 2\. How we use the information

### Creators:

We process personal data about Creators for a variety of purposes:

  * To provide Creators with our services.
  * To enforce our Terms of Service and prevent potentially illegal or abusive activity.
  * To contact Creators about their service or account. We occasionally send communications (e.g., service-related announcements, changes to our services or policies, billing-related matters, a welcome email when Creators first register).
  * To contact Creators for marketing purposes. We will only do this if Creators have consented to receive these communications. Creators may opt-out of these communications at any time by changing the relevant setting on the Profile page.

### Respondents:

All information that Respondents provide in response to a survey will be provided to the Survey Creator. Survey responses are owned and managed by the Survey Creator, and we treat that information as private to the Survey Creator. The Survey Creator controls the survey and what happens to the survey data. We recommend that Respondents contact the Survey Creator running the survey to understand how they will use their survey responses. The Survey Creator may provide Respondents with their own privacy policy governing the use of survey data. We will not provide any information that Respondents submit in response to the survey to third parties.

## 3\. With whom do we share or disclose information

### Creators:

We do not share personal data with any third parties except in the following very limited circumstances:

  * Manage customer support.
  * Making credit card payments.
  * Sending surveys by email to Respondents.

We enter into confidentiality and data processing terms with partners to ensure they comply with high levels of confidentiality and best practice in privacy and security standards and we regularly review these standards and practices.

### Respondents:

We disclose Respondent survey responses to Survey Creators. We host surveys for Survey Creators, but they are the primary collector of survey data. Anything Respondents expressly disclose in survey responses will, naturally, be provided to Survey Creators. Please contact the Survey Creator directly to understand how they might share Respondent survey responses.

## 5\. Security, cookies and other information

  * **Security:** The security of information is important to us, and we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. All information that users provide to us is stored on secure servers. When users submit information, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). Where users use a password to access certain areas of our website they are responsible for keeping this password confidential and must not share it with anyone. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information and data submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. Once we have received users' information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.
  * **Cookies:** Survs uses cookies to administer the website. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if they choose to disable cookies, it may limit their use of certain features or functions on our website or service.
  * **Changes to this privacy policy:** This privacy policy may be changed. If we make any material changes, we will notify users using a notice on this website before the change becoming effective. We encourage users periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## 6\. Additional information for European Union users

Survs is compliant with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). This regulation is designed to give European Union citizens more control over their data and seeks to unify existing privacy and security laws under one comprehensive scheme.

### Data controller

Survs is the data controller for registration, billing and other account information that we collect from users in the EU. However, the data controller for survey data is the Survey Creator. The Survey Creator determines how their survey questions and responses are used and disclosed. Survs only processes such survey data in accordance with the instructions and permissions (including those given under this privacy policy) selected by the Survey Creator when they create and administer their survey.

### Your rights

European Union users have certain legal rights to obtain information about whether we hold personal information about them, to access personal information we hold about them, and to obtain its correction, update, amendment or deletion. We will respond to your request to exercise these rights within a reasonable time, within 30 days of receiving a request. 

Rights which you are entitled to are:

  * Data access rights
  * Right to restrict processing
  * Right of Rectification
  * Right to Erasure (Right to be Forgotten)
  * Right to object to processing
  * Right to withdraw consent
  * Data portability rights

### Exercising your rights

Issues regarding GDPR can be directed to:

Enough Pepper Lda.  
Attn: Information Commissioner's Office  
Avenida da República 6, 7 Esq  
1050-191 Lisboa  
Portugal  

## 7\. Contact Us

If you have questions or concerns about Survs' Privacy Policy please contact us at support@survs.com or Avenida da República 6, 7 Esq 1050-191 Lisboa, Portugal Attn: Privacy Department.
